Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40", 111340
  - Sandby, Paul (1731-1809), 111381
    - "A View in Hudson's River of Pakepsey & the Catts-Kill Mountain, from Sopos Island in Hudson's River", 1761; 111385 (Box Unknown container 898 for instance of "A View in Hudson's River of Pakepsey & the Catts-Kill Mountain, from Sopos Island in Hudson's River", Folder unknown container)
    - "A View of the Great Cohoes Falls on the Mohawk River", 1761; 111384 (Box Unknown container 899 for instance of "A View of the Great Cohoes Falls on the Mohawk River", Folder unknown container)
      painted by Sandby, engraved by William Elliot, published by Thomas Jefferys, London. Two additional copies of a later issue.
    - "A View of Bethlem, the Great Moravian Settlement in the Province of Pennsylvania", 1761; 111383 (Box Unknown container 900 for instance of "A View of Bethlem, the Great Moravian Settlement in the Province of Pennsylvania", Folder unknown container)
      painted and engraved by Sandby, published by Thomas Jefferys, London.
    - "A Design to Represent the Beginning and Completion of an American Settlement or Farm", 1761; 111382 (Box Unknown container 901 for instance of "A Design to Represent the Beginning and Completion of an American Settlement or Farm", Folder unknown container)
      painted by Sandby, engraved by James Peake, published by Thomas Jefferys, London. Two copies, one additional copy of a later issue.
  - Schwartz, Peri (b. 1951), 111376
    - "Woman on subway", 111380 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
      artist's proof
    - "Subway" (2/25), 1977; 111379 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - "Grand Army Plaza I" (1/1), 1979; 111378 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - "Reading Room II" (1/1), 1976; 111377 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
  - Scott, Dread (b. 1965), 111369
    - "Triangle Shirt Waste", 2001; 111375 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
      Sceen print on paper, 7/14
    - "We are the 99%", 2011; 111374 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
      Screen print on paper, 2/7
    - "We are the 99%-Arabic", 2011; 111373 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
    - "Eimazte to 99%", 2011; 111372 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
    - "Somos El 99%", 2011; 111371 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
      Screen print on paper 2/7
    - "Siamo Il 99%", 2011; 111370 (Box FF, Folder unknown container)
  - Seymour, Samuel (fl. 1797-1823), 111367
    after William Birch (1755-1834).
    - "The City of New York in the State of New York North America", 1803; 111368 (Box Unknown container 902 for instance of "The City of New York in the State of New York North America", Folder unknown container)
      engraving, published by William Birch, Pennsylvania. One copy of first state, colored, and one copy of third state [with added picnickers and William Morgan's imprint, ca. 1820], uncolored
  - Simon, Tavik Frantisek (1877-1942), 20535
    - [Broad Street with New York Stock Exchange], 1927; 20539 (Box Unknown container 903 for instance of [Broad Street with New York Stock Exchange], Folder unknown container)
      color aquatint
    - [Broadway at night], [1927]; 20538 (Box Unknown container 904 for instance of [Broadway at night], Folder unknown container)
    - [New York Public Library in winter], 1927; 20537 (Box Unknown container 905 for instance of [New York Public Library in winter], Folder unknown container)
    - [View of Lower Manhattan from Brooklyn Bridge walkway at dusk], [1927]; 20536 (Box Unknown container 906 for instance of [View of Lower Manhattan from Brooklyn Bridge walkway at dusk], Folder unknown container)
  - Sloat, Richard Joel (b. 1945), 20531
    - Not So Flat Iron(2/50), 1996; 20534 (Box Unknown container 907 for instance of Not So Flat Iron(2/50), Folder unknown container)
      woodblock print
    - Rising Sun (35/90), 1977; 20533 (Box Unknown container 908 for instance of Rising Sun (35/90), Folder unknown container)
    - Walk Down St. Marks (5/90), 1994; 20532 (Box Unknown container 909 for instance of Walk Down St. Marks (5/90), Folder unknown container)
  - Smillie, James (1807-1885), 111362
    after Thomas Cole (1801-1848).
    - "Voyage of Life, Childhood", undated; 111366 (Box Unknown container 910 for instance of "Voyage of Life, Childhood", Folder unknown container)
      proof with no publisher listed, printed by H. Peters
    - "Voyage of Life, Youth", undated; 111365 (Box Unknown container 911 for instance of "Voyage of Life, Youth", Folder unknown container)
      printed by J. Dalton
    - "Voyage of Life, Manhood", undated; 111364 (Box Unknown container 912 for instance of "Voyage of Life, Manhood", Folder unknown container)
    - "Voyage of Life, Old Age", undated; 111363 (Box Unknown container 913 for instance of "Voyage of Life, Old Age", Folder unknown container)
  - Smith, Samuel, 111360
    after Thomas Leitch (fl. 1771).
    - "A View of Charles-Town, the Capitol of South Carolina", 1776; 111361 (Box Unknown container 914 for instance of "A View of Charles-Town, the Capitol of South Carolina", Folder unknown container)
      published by Smith, London
  - Soyer, Raphael (1899-1987), 114585
    - Immigrants, 1969; 114586 (Box-folder .)
      Lithograph. Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Stadler, Joseph Constantine (fl. 1780-1812), 111358
    after William Roberts (1788-1867).
    - "The Natural Bridge", 1808; 111359 (Box Unknown container 915 for instance of "The Natural Bridge", Folder unknown container)
      colored aquatint, published in London
  - Strickland, William (1788-1854), 111355
    - "Monumental Church at Richmond", [1810]; 111357 (Box Unknown container 916 for instance of "Monumental Church at Richmond", Folder unknown container)
      perspective and engraving by Strickland, aquatinted by William Kneass, published by William Kneass
    - "View of the Water Gap and Columbia Glassworks--River Delaware", [1815-1818]; 111356 (Box Unknown container 917 for instance of "View of the Water Gap and Columbia Glassworks--River Delaware", Folder unknown container)
      aquatint after Thomas Birch, 1779-1851. Two copies, one colored.
  - Tiebout, Cornelius (ca. 1777-ca. 1830), 111351
    - "A View of Rensselaerville Manufactory The Property of Mr. James Caldwell, of the City of Albany, Merchant, with a Distant Prospect of Hudsons River and the Seat of Stephen Van Rensselaer Esquire", 1792; 111354 (Box Unknown container 918 for instance of "A View of Rensselaerville Manufactory The Property of Mr. James Caldwell, of the City of Albany, Merchant, with a Distant Prospect of Hudsons River and the Seat of Stephen Van Rensselaer Esquire", Folder unknown container)
    - "Loss of the Packet Ship Albion", undated; 111353 (Box Unknown container 919 for instance of "Loss of the Packet Ship Albion", Folder unknown container)
      after Thomas Birch, 1779-1851, printed by William H. Morgan, Philadelphia. Two copies.
    - "View in Noble Borough State of New York", undated; 111352 (Box Unknown container 920 for instance of "View in Noble Borough State of New York", Folder unknown container)
  - Trueblood, Emily (b. 1942), 20528
    - City Towers (2/50), 1994; 20530 (Box Unknown container 921 for instance of City Towers (2/50), Folder unknown container)
    - Night Tower (31/50), 2000; 20529 (Box Unknown container 922 for instance of Night Tower (31/50), Folder unknown container)
  - Varian, George (1865-1923), 111348
    - [Jeremiah Vanderbilt House, Flatbush Ave.], [1911]; 111350 (Box Unknown container 923 for instance of [Jeremiah Vanderbilt House, Flatbush Ave.], Folder unknown container)
      Two copies, one a canceled plate
    - [Unidentified historic Brooklyn house], [1911]; 111349 (Box Unknown container 924 for instance of [Unidentified historic Brooklyn house], Folder unknown container)
  - Wallace, William H., 20521
    - Harlem River in 1870, 20527 (Box Unknown container 925 for instance of Harlem River in 1870, Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882; 20526 (Box Unknown container 926 for instance of Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882; 20525 (Box Unknown container 927 for instance of Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), Folder unknown container)
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890; 20524 (Box Unknown container 928 for instance of [New York from Staten Island (?)], Folder unknown container)
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888; 20523 (Box Unknown container 929 for instance of [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], Folder unknown container)
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated; 20522 (Box Unknown container 930 for instance of [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], Folder unknown container)
  - Wallace, William H., 111343
    - [Farmhouse], undated; 111347 (Box Unknown container 931 for instance of [Farmhouse], Folder unknown container)
    - [Man fishing], undated; 111346 (Box Unknown container 932 for instance of [Man fishing], Folder unknown container)
    - [Man on horseback in forest], undated; 111345 (Box Unknown container 933 for instance of [Man on horseback in forest], Folder unknown container)
    - [Rabbit by stream], undated; 111344 (Box Unknown container 934 for instance of [Rabbit by stream], Folder unknown container)
  - Welling, Richard (1926-2009), 111752
    - From Brooklyn Bridge (164/200), 1976; 111753 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - Singer Building Demolition, 1967; 111754 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
    - Untitled [construction of World Trade Center?], undated; 111755 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
  - Werger, Art (b.1955), 20519
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997; 20520 (Box Unknown container 935 for instance of Daybreak (56/75), Folder unknown container)
  - Whitman, Karen (b. 1953), 20517
    - Downtown (15/85), 2003; 20518 (Box Unknown container 936 for instance of Downtown (15/85), Folder unknown container)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988), 20511
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938; 20516 (Box Unknown container 937 for instance of Manhattan Mountains, Folder unknown container)
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated; 20515 (Box Unknown container 938 for instance of The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), Folder unknown container)
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988; 20514 (Box Unknown container 939 for instance of Under the Bridge (6/27), Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976; 20513 (Box Unknown container 940 for instance of [Produce stands] (7/75), Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976; 20512 (Box Unknown container 941 for instance of [Produce stands] (9/75), Folder unknown container)
  - Wilson, James & Isaac Eddy, 111341
    - "Chronology Delineated to Illustrate the History of Monarchical Revolution", 1813; 111342 (Box Unknown container 942 for instance of "Chronology Delineated to Illustrate the History of Monarchical Revolution", Folder unknown container)
      published by Eddy, Vermont. Two copies, one colored, and another copy of the bottom half of the plate.
  - Unidentified artist, 112060
    - New York from Jersey shore by night, undated; 112061 (Box Flat files, Folder unknown container)
- Series III: Prints larger than 30 x 40", 111299
  Series III. Prints larger than 30 x 40" includes prints stored in frames and in oversize drawers.
  William Burgis' "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York" is widely considered to be the most important early view of New York. The print was originally printed in London on four sheets of paper and published in 1719-1721. In 1746, the plates were changed somewhat and the print reissued by Thomas Bakewell. A copy of each of the states is included in this series. Additionally, Burgis' 1722 view of Boston can be found here.
  - Burgis, William (fl. 1716-1731), 111336
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York in the Province of New York in America", ca. 1719-1721; 111339 (Box Framed - hanging on wall in 2NW, Folder unknown container)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739)
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Flourishing City of New York in the Province of New York in America", 1746; 111338 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Burgis)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739), printed and sold by Thomas Bakewell, London. State II.
    - "A South Prospect of Ye Great Town of Boston in New England in America", 1722; 111337 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Burgis)
      line engraving designed by Burgis, engraved by John Harris (fl. 1685-1739), printed and sold by William Price, Boston.
      See also: Series I.
  - Behnken, William (b. 1943), 111334
    - Lightscapes (3/50), 2003; 111335 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder A-D)
  - Bury, Pol, 111332
    - [Guggenheim], undated; 111333 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder A-D)
  - Eller, Evelyn (b. 1833), 111329
    - "My New York", 1998; 111331 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Eller, Evelyn)
      Mixed media collage unique Artist Book
    - "Immigration", 1999; 111330 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Eller, Evelyn)
      Paper collage
  - Grooms, Red (b. 1937), 111325
    - On Your Mark, Set, Go! (9/72), 2002; 111328 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Ruckus Taxi, 1982; 111327 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Subway (40/75), 1971; 111326 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
  - Haas, Richard (b. 1936), 111319
    - Flatiron Building (11/60), 1973; 111324 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Little Singer Building (36/40), 1971; 111323 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - Manhattan View, Governor's Island, 1999; 111322 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
    - George Washington Bridge (38/200), 1999; 111321 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Hass, Richard)
      aluminum print
    - Manhattan Bridge (65/200), 1999; 111320 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder Hass, Richard)
  - Harris, Arthur John (b. 1959), 111317
    - Flatiron (1/150), 111318 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder F-H)
  - Jacquette, Yvonne (b. 1934), 111315
    - New York Harbor Composite, 2003; 111316 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
  - McPherson, Craig (b. 1948), 111313
    - FDR Drive, 1993; 111314 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
  - Morper, Daniel (b. 1944), 111311
    - "Metropolis" (26/100), 1989; 111312 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder I-R)
      etching with aquatint
  - Seltzer, Phyllis (b. 1928), 111308
    - Intersection, 2001; 111310 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder [too large for folder - at bottom of drawer])
      heat transfer print
    - Time out (3/3), 2003; 111309 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Werger, Art (b. 1955), 111304
    - Attraction, 2003; 111305 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Yewell, J. Floyd, 111300
    - George Washington Bridge (19/150), 1931; 111303 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
    - George Washington Bridge, 1931; 111302 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
    - Goethals Bridge (59/150), undated; 111301 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)
  - Unidentified artist, 111306
    - "White Column Facade", 1999; 111307 (Box Oversize flat files, Folder S-Z)